Creative full-stack developer focusing on front-end with 4+ years of freelance experience providing high-impact web applications for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in design, development and testing multiple web-based apps incorporating a range of technologies. Aspiring to combine experience with strong technical and managerial skills to excel as full-stack developer.

## **EDUCATION**

**B.Tech Computer Science**, Cochin University of Science and Technology Jul 2018 - Jul 2022 | Kochi, India

## **CGPA: 8.45**

- Chairman, IEEE Computer Society.
- Co-lead, Google Developer Students Club.
- Head of Technology, TEDxCUSAT.
- Google CloudReady Facilitator for CUSAT.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Software Engineering Intern,** Open Water Accelerator ☑

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020 | Menlo Park, CA, US

Responsibilities: UI Design, Development, unit testing and documentation.

- Reduced analysis time for Enterprise clients by 30% implementing Maps Analytics Dashboard using Mapbox API, React and Django.
- Improved performance by 20% by fixing application-wide bugs and refactoring code.
- Liaised with back end, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and managers as needed.

Design & Development Intern, Hapiens Digital Pvt Ltd.

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020 | Kochi, India

Responsibilities: UI/UX Design and Fullstack Development.

- Developed a telegram bot to automate messaging which boosted productivity.
- Automated and scaled complex manual company tasks and workflows.
- Collaborated with the team, participated in meetings and presented innovative ideas.

UI/UX Research Intern, CodeSteak LLP ☑

Jun 2019 | Kochi, India

Responsibilities: UI Design and prototyping.

# **LEADERSHIP POSITIONS & VOLUNTEERING**

Google Developers Group, Cochin (Organizer)

Hello Munnar project by Kerala Govt. and Kites Foundation. (Front-end Lead)

**TinkerHub Foundation** (Community Contributor)

**Dhishna Techfest** (Head of Design & Media.)

Innovators' Summit (Head of Media & Organizer)

## **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

Mentoring, Speaking, Research, Music, Films & T.V series, Football, Videography and production

#### **SKILLS**

Soft Skills (Problem Solving, Leadership, Multitasking, Programming, Networking, Communication, Teamwork.)

Development Skills (Javascript, Python, React.js, Node.js, Git, Three.js, SQL, MongoDB, Firebase.)

Design Skills (UI Design, UI prototyping, Adobe XD, Framer, Figma, After Effects.)

#### **PROJECTS**

**Google Cloud Ready Facilitator Dashboard,** This Application automates the 2+ hrs of Daily manual student report generation of GCR facilitator.

**Graphs Visualizer,** A Visualizer that allows you to draw directed graphs and shows the corresponding matrices. Visualization of various algorithms are to be implemented in future releases. ☑

## Daily Messages Telegram Scheduler, A

Telegram Bot that posts scheduled message with images and caption. Stack: Node.js + MongoDB ☑

# **Doctor Patient Record System, A**

doctor-patient management system. Doctors can add prescription and medical history. Patients can view their 

**RefractionX Simulation, Interactive** physics simulation on refraction made using Javascrpit and HTML+CSS.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# Top 3 Projects,

Open Water Accelerator Hackathon

Selected for InOut 6.0 Hackathon from a pool of 1000s of Nation-wide applicants.

Top Contributor, Code4Munnar

**SUSE Cloud Native Foundations** Scholarship, Udacity 🗷